# Dan Huynh

□ 226-606-9284 | @ dan.huynh@uwaterloo.ca | in LinkedIn | ♥ GitHub | ♥ Portfolio

## **O**VERVIEW

Languages: C/C++, Java/Scala, Python, TypeScript, GO, PHP, SQL, Swift, MATLAB, VHDL Technologies: Docker, Azure, GCP, AWS, Node, Spring, React, Angular, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, ROS2, OpenCV 5+ years of experience in designing mechanical equipment using SolidWorks and the Autodesk suite

## Professional Experience

#### Data Science Engineer @ theScore

Sept 2024 - Dec 2024

- Performed exploratory data analyses with **Pandas** and **Sklearn** to identify and improve under-performing betting markets, capturing game-time effects on pitcher performance and improving the RMSE, R<sup>2</sup>, and market odds deviations of an **MLflow** PCA-based total pitches model and logistic regression stolen base projections by 46.13%, 46.18%, and 56%, respectively.
- Designed a configuration-driven **Python** data monitor for rapidly scaling, sport agnostic, odds projection models, validating projection availability, data sparsity across 27+ tables in **BigQuery** and **PostgreSQL**, and anomaly detection using distributional divergence and z-score metrics which trigger alerts to **Slack** and **DataDog**.
- Developed an automated, scalable testing framework using Pytest, Tox, and GitHub Actions to unit, integration, and contract test machine learning services and Argo Workflow DAG nodes, reducing pipeline errors in production.
- Built an **Argo Workflow** for dynamic table data migration between **BigQuery** and **PostgreSQL** schemas, avoiding **GCP** rate limits for 10M+ row transfers while ensuring row uniqueness and schema consistency.

#### Software Development Engineer in Test @ Vivid Seats

Jan 2024 - Apr 2024

- Designed a **Stoplight**-documented test-data Backend for Frontend (BFF) with **Spring**, exposing RESTful endpoints for **JPA** entity generation and management that insert regression-agnostic data for E2E checkout tests into 4+ vault-authenticated **AWS Aurora** databases, resulting in a 60% build time reduction.
- Created a distributed subscriber for the test-data BFF which enables on-demand and autonomous data cleanup via client API calls and a proprietary cleanup micro-service, allowing for concurrent data management.
- Integrated **SonarQube** for static code analysis, leading to the development of 210+ unit and integration tests using **JUnit5**, **Mockito**, and **Spring** that achieved 96% code coverage for the test-data BFF.

#### Data Scientist @ PureFacts Financial Solutions

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Developed and tuned an **Sklearn** bayesian optimized random forest regressor with a mean percentage error of 17. 32% that predicts client revenue movements, while providing explanations for model predictions using **SHAP**.
- Built a dashboard using **Plotly Dash** that features dynamic visualizations of investor revenue, AUM, transactions, and customer trends over time for PureFacts clients, enabling data-driven decision making.
- Led development of a **Flask** + **React** tool tailored to the PureFacts tech stack utilizing **OpenAI APIs** that empower non-technical personnel with accessible information and reduces engineer labor time while maintaining data confidentiality.

#### Software Engineer @ Ford Motor Company

Sept 2022 - Dec 2022

- Created components including a data-model agnostic fuzzy search component using **React Typescript**, which queries 1000+ **Firestore** records for objects that fit a Regex string on one of 7+ record properties.
- Wrote asynchronous RESTful methods using Axios that reads/writes to 1000+ records in a Firestore database.

## **PROJECTS**

# Perceptions Lead @ Watonomous — LiDar Object Detection | Github

Sept 2023 -Sept 2024

- Designed a data loader for **OpenPCDet** to processes 32-beam, 4/5 feature Velodyne point clouds into **NumPy** arrays, optimized for **VoxelNeXt**, **TransFusion**, and **PV-RCNN** predictions.
- Wrapped **OpenPCDet** in a **ROS2-humble** node that processes a point cloud rosbag feed, publishing real-time bounding box predictions through the **Foxglove** WebSocket protocol for immediate data visualization.
- Modified **OpenPCDet** visualization utilities to render static **PV-RCNN** bounding-box predictions using **XVFB**, ensuring compatibility without reliance on a native **X-11 server**.
- Collaborated in the design and implementation of a end-to-end perceptions pipeline that tracks and associates objects in real time.

#### EDUCATION